<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Grant&#39;s Election Blog</title>
    <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Grant&#39;s Election Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 9: Final Prediction</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/11/03/week-9-final-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/11/03/week-9-final-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this final blog post, published two days before the election (Sunday Nov 3), I am going to explain how I prepared my final model and the results derived from it.&#xA;Before I do so, however, I want to share what is perhaps my main takeaway from this class thus far:&#xA;Predicting elections is hard.&#xA;In many ways, it is a somewhat impossible task. Forecasting elections is not difficult because procuring data is challenging or because training models is computationally expensive; rather, predicting the outcomes of US elections is fundamentally hard because there are relatively few elections from which we can construct our models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: Penultimate Week</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/10/26/week-8-penultimate-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/10/26/week-8-penultimate-week/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this eighth blog post, in the second-to-last week before the 2024 election, I want to improve my election forecasts for the seven battleground states.&#xA;Over the past several weeks, we have explored OLS models, incumbency bias, the relationship between turnout and demographics, Bayesian approaches to predictions, and logistic regression, among other topics.&#xA;One thing that has consistently bothered me about the models I have constructed up to this point has been my fairly arbitrary standard deviation estimate when creating simulations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 7: Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/10/19/week-7-logic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/10/19/week-7-logic-regression/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this seventh blog post, I am going to explore the use of logistic regression as opposed to linear regression while creating my models and simulations and evaluate how my electoral college projections change.&#xA;My projections from last week (which used elastic net linear regression) are available here.&#xA;The code used to produce these visualizations is publicly available in my github repository and draws heavily from the section notes and sample code provided by the Gov 1347 Head Teaching Fellow, Matthew Dardet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Bayesian Approach</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/10/12/week-6-bayesian-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/10/12/week-6-bayesian-approach/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this sixth blog post, I am going to discuss the role that ads play in elections, and, then, I will discuss how a Frequentist approach to polling compares to a Bayesian approach.&#xA;I will also be updating my model from last week.&#xA;The code used to produce these visualizations is publicly available in my github repository and draws heavily from the section notes and sample code provided by the Gov 1347 Head Teaching Fellow, Matthew Dardet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Five: Turnout</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/10/02/week-5-turnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/10/02/week-5-turnout/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this fifth blog post, I am going to discuss two areas of election forecasting: turnout and demographics.&#xA;Then, I am going to prepare a baseline model to predict the 2024 election. Over the next 4 weeks until the November 5th election, I will fine tune this model and ultimately use it to predict the next president of the United States of America.&#xA;The code used to produce these visualizations is publicly available in my github repository and draws heavily from the section notes and sample code provided by the Gov 1347 Head Teaching Fellow, Matthew Dardet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Four - Incumbency</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/29/week-four-incumbency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/29/week-four-incumbency/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this fourth blog post, I want to explore the subject of incumbency.&#xA;In the 11 presidential elections since 1948 in which the incumbent president was running, the incumbent&amp;rsquo;s bid was successful 7 times. As a percentage, this is roughly 64% of the time.&#xA;Political pundits have long identified this apparent benefit of currently holding the political office for which one is running as incumbency advantage.&#xA;One need only take a look at the House reelection rates among incumbent candidates to see clear evidence of this advantage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Three - Polls</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/23/week-three-polls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/23/week-three-polls/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this third blog post, I want to explore how we can best use polls to predict election outcomes. I will do this through the following steps:&#xA;1) First, I am going to visualize poll accuracy over time. 2) Next, I will use various regularization techniques to create a model that will predict the 2024 election. 3) Then, I will use ensemble learning methods to combine models that incorporate both fundamental (economic) and polling data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week Two - OLS</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/16/week-two-ols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/16/week-two-ols/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this second blog post, I want to explore&#xA;1) whether it is possible to predict election outcomes using only the state of the economy 2) and, if so, how well The code used to produce these visualizations is publicly available in my github repository and draws heavily from the section notes and sample code provided by the Gov 1347 Head Teaching Fellow, Matthew Dardet.&#xA;Analysis To begin to answer the first question of whether it is possible to predict election outcomes using only the state of the economy, I will merge Federal Reserve Economic Data from the St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week One - Basic Model</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/09/week-one-basic-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/09/week-one-basic-model/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this first blog post, my goal is to explore two central questions:&#xA;1) How competitive are presidential elections in the United States? 2) Which states vote blue/red and how consistently? At the end of this blog post, I will also be sharing my first electoral map prediction for the 2024 presidential election. Each week from here on out, I will be updating this model to consider additional predictors like real-time polling averages, historical trends in the electoral college, demographic changes in the United States, and economic conditions, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
