<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Grant&#39;s Election Blog</title>
    <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Grant&#39;s Election Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week Two - OLS</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/16/week-two-ols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/16/week-two-ols/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this second blog post, I want to explore&#xA;1) whether it is possible to predict election outcomes using only the state of the economy 2) and, if so, how well The code used to produce these visualizations is publicly available in my github repository and draws heavily from the section notes and sample code provided by the Gov 1347 Head Teaching Fellow, Matthew Dardet.&#xA;Analysis To begin to answer the first question of whether it is possible to predict election outcomes using only the state of the economy, I will merge Federal Reserve Economic Data from the St.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week One - Basic Model</title>
      <link>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/09/week-one-basic-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://grantbw4.github.io/election-blog/post/2024/09/09/week-one-basic-model/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this first blog post, my goal is to explore two central questions:&#xA;1) How competitive are presidential elections in the United States? 2) Which states vote blue/red and how consistently? At the end of this blog post, I will also be sharing my first electoral map prediction for the 2024 presidential election. Each week from here on out, I will be updating this model to consider additional predictors like real-time polling averages, historical trends in the electoral college, demographic changes in the United States, and economic conditions, etc.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
